
import 'question_model.dart';

List<QuestionModel> questions =  [
  QuestionModel(
    question: '1. What type of paradigm does Flutter use for building user interfaces?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'A) Imperative',
      'B) Declarative',
      'C) Procedural',
      'D) Object-Oriented',
    ],
  ),
  QuestionModel(
    question: '2. Which programming language is used in Flutter development?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'A) Java',
      'B) Dart',
      'C) Kotlin',
      'D) Swift',
    ],
  ),
  QuestionModel(
    question: '3. What does the term "hot reload" mean in Flutter?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'A) Restarting the app',
      'B) Updating the app in real-time during development',
      'C) Creating a new release build',
      'D) Running tests automatically',
    ],
  ),
  QuestionModel(
    question: '4. Which widget is considered the foundation for building Flutter layouts?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'A) Scaffold',
      'B) Container',
      'C) MaterialApp',
      'D) StatelessWidget',
    ],
  ),
  QuestionModel(
    question: '5. What is Dart, and how is it related to Flutter?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'A) Dart is the programming language used in Flutter.',
      'B) Dart is a design pattern in Flutter.',
      'C) Dart is a database system used by Flutter.',
      'D) Dart is the framework for Flutter.',
    ],
  ),
  QuestionModel(
    question: '6. What is the purpose of the "pubspec.yaml" file in a Flutter project?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'A) To define project dependencies',
      'B) To store user preferences',
      'C) To specify the project structure',
      'D) To configure the app\'s theme',
    ],
  ),
  QuestionModel(
    question: '7. In Flutter, what is the significance of the "BuildContext"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'A) Managing app navigation',
      'B) Providing access to the location of a widget in the widget tree',
      'C) Defining the app\'s theme',
      'D) Handling user input events',
    ],
  ),
  QuestionModel(
    question: '8. What is the primary function of the "setState" method in Flutter?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'A) Initializing the state of a widget',
      'B) Triggering a rebuild of the widget tree with a new state',
      'C) Creating a new instance of a widget',
      'D) Updating the app\'s configuration',
    ],
  ),
  QuestionModel(
    question: '9. Which of the following is a stateless widget in Flutter?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'A) StatelessWidget',
      'B) MaterialApp',
      'C) Scaffold',
      'D) StatefulBuilder',
    ],
  ),
  QuestionModel(
    question: '10. What is the purpose of the "async" and "await" keywords in Dart?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'A) Controlling the app\'s layout',
      'B) Handling asynchronous operations',
      'C) Defining animation sequences',
      'D) Specifying font styles',
    ],
  ),
];
